Ronny Martin Condor Iturrizaga

Variation Lima, Peru Salation (+51) 953 596 865 ✓ rmcondorit@gmail.com Personal site

Bachelor's degree in Economics from the Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos. Interest in research on development economics, applied microeconomics, education, and poverty.

EDUCATION

Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos, Lima, Perú

Faculty of Economics Sciences, Bachelor in Economics Belonging to the highest quintile March 2016-December 2020

EXPERIENCE

Innovations for Poverty Action (IPA)

Research Associate Oct 2021 - present

Research design and data collection for a Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT) of Belizean students that aims to increase the intention to study STEM careers.

Research Analyst

December 2020-September 2021

Collaboration in projects about Early Childhood Development in El Salvador and Entrepreneurial Mindset Training in Ecuador. Support in instruments review, data management, fieldwork monitoring and data analysis.

Office of the Comptroller General of Peru

Consultant

July 2020-November 2020

Collaboration in the project called "Improvement of Control Services for the Effective, Preventive and Enabling Control of Public Management" financed by the Inter-American Development Bank and the Office of the Comptroller General of Peru.

Videnza Consultores

Intern

January 2020-July 2020

Writing quantitative results of economic studies commissioned by private, public, and international institutions. Data collection and data management. Moreover, support in qualitative research projects.

TEACHING

Teaching Assistant

Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos

March 2019-July 2019

- Economics of Distribution (Github repo)
- Econometrics I

— ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

La Rotonda Blog

Director

April 2020 - July 2022

La Rotonda is a non-profit organization whose main objective is the free dissemination of knowledge in the different branches of Economics and the promotion of opportunities across diverse groups in Peru.

Workshop speaker

2019-2021

- Intermediate Stata course (in representation of IPA in the Eco-mienza program of the Econthaki organization)
- Towards other approaches: The contribution of Georgescu-Roegen's bioeconomics.
- Introductory Stata course (Github repo)

SKILLS

- Languages: Spanish (native) English (advanced)
- Software: Stata, R, LATEX, Markdown, Git, Survey CTO, Kobo Toolbox.

PUBLICATIONS

Campos, G. y Condor, R. (2022). Ethnicity in Peru and its multidimensional nature: a proposal for measurement. Desde el Sur. (Original in Spanish)

WORK IN PROGRESS

Does trade openness have an effect on wage inequality? Evidence from Peru.

COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION

Manage Successful Impact Evaluation Surveys course

World Bank, Development Impact Evaluation (DIME) department

June 2022

MicroMaster in Data, Economics, and Development Policy

Massachusetts Institute Technology in edX (MITx)

 $June \ 2022$

Completed: Microeconomics, Data Analysis for Social Scientists, Designing and Running Randomized Evaluations

US Research Staff Training

Abdul Latif Jameel Poverty Action Lab (J-PAL)

Nov 2021

Data for Better Lives: A New Social Contract

World Bank Group in edX (WBGx)

Nov 2021

Preparation of quantitative research proposals

Consorcio de investigación económica y social (CIES)

June 2020

Designing a Multidimensional Poverty Index

Oxford Poverty & Human Development Initiative (OPHI)

April 2020